Guide to the Roy Rosenzweig papers, 1934-2007
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 5: Oral History, 1970-2007; (7 boxes)
  - Oral History and Computers, 1980s (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Oral History and the Law, 1985 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Oral History Association Pamphlets, 1980s-1990s (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - Oral History at Columbia, 1992 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Oral History Class #4, 1982 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Oral History Community Class, 1982 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Oral History Conferences, 1985 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Oral History Continuing Education, 1982 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - Oral History Course, 1983 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - Oral History Course: Interviewing and Interpretation, 1970s-1980s (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - Oral History Excluded from IRB Review, 2000s (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - Oral History Interviewing Class, 1980s (Box 81, Folder 1)
  - Oral History Materials (misc.), 1980s (Box 81, Folder 2)
  - Oral History of the WPA Arts Project, 1982 (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Oral History Order, 1980s-1990s (Box 81, Folder 4)
  - Oral History Papers, Notes and Pamphlets, 1970s-1980s (Box 81, Folder 5)
  - Oral History Papers, Notes and Pamphlets, 1970s-1980s (Box 81, Folder 6)
  - Oral History Papers, Notes and Pamphlets, 1970s (Box 81, Folder 7)
  - Oral History Project Friends of Greenwich Library, 1982 (Box 81, Folder 8)
  - Oral History Volunteers, 1984 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Oral History Workshop in Arlington, 1982 (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Oral History: Listening to Tapes, 1980s (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - Over 1800 Little Blue Books, undated (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Overview and Introduction for the Oral History Association, 2003 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Panel on United Packinghouse Workers Oral History Project, 1987 (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Partnow: Homelessness, undated (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Partnow: Homelessness, undated (Box 82, Folder 8)
  - Personality Sketch of Isaac M. Warren, undated (Box 82, Folder 9)
  - Plant, Thomas, undated (Box 82, Folder 10)
  - Posters from the Federal Theater Project, 1991 (Box 82, Folder 11)
  - Public History "To-Do" List, 1980s (Box 82, Folder 12)
  - Record Group 69 (Life Histories), 1980s (Box 82, Folder 13)
  - Robinson, Earl, 1980s (Box 82, Folder 14)
  - Selections From the National Colloquia on Oral History, 1970-1971 (Box 82, Folder 15)
  - Senior Officer Oral History Program, 1981 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - Smith, Essie (Life Histories), 1940 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Summary Report of Life Histories, 1980s (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - Talking About Connecticut: Oral History in the Nutmeg State, 1985 (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - Techniques for Oral History Interviewing, 1980s (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - The Appalachian Oral History Program Union Catalogue, 1977 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - The Courier of Historical Events, 1989 (Box 83, Folder 7)
  - The G.I. Movement Oral History Project, 1991 (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - The Maryland Historian Oral History Issue, 1982 (Box 83, Folder 9)
  - The Oral History Collections of the Minnesota Historical Society, 1984 (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - The Role of Local History, 1980 (Box 83, Folder 11)
  - Touchstones: Landmarks and People in Western Fairfax County, 1986 (Box 83, Folder 12)
  - Transcribing and Editing Oral History, undated (Box 83, Folder 13)
  - Venable, Mary S. (Life Histories), 1977 (Box 83, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Life Histories FWP, 1993 (Box 83, Folder 15)
  - Voluntary Historians in Virginia, 1992 (Box 83, Folder 16)
  - WPA General Notes, 1980s-1990s (Box 83, Folder 17)
  - WPA non New York, 1980s-1990s (Box 83, Folder 18)
- Series 6: Digital History, 1988-2007; (9 boxes)
  The Digital History Series contains information about new media and how it can both change and enhances classroom, research, and teaching experiences.
  - Abbote, Janet, 1994 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - ACLS, 1998-2004 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Advancing the Humanities Through Technology, 1999 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - Agre, Phil, 2000-2001 (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Agre, Phil, 2000-2001 (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - AHA Paper, 1996-1997 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - American Museum of the Moving Image, 1983 (Box 84, Folder 7)
  - American Social History Project, 1990s (Box 84, Folder 8)
  - American Social History Project, 1990s (Box 84, Folder 9)
  - American Social History Project, 1990s (Box 84, Folder 10)
  - ARPA NET Thesis, 1996 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Benkler, 2005 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Beyond Digitalization Precis for NEH, 2007 (Box 85, Folder 3)
  - Book Proposal, 2002 (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - Center for History and New Media Ph.D. Program, 1999 (Box 85, Folder 5)
  - Change: The Magazine of Higher Learning, 1996-1997 (Box 85, Folder 6)
  - Chat room Transcription, 2001 (Box 85, Folder 7)
  - Clio Wired, 1996 (Box 85, Folder 8)
  - CRM: Cultural Resources and the World Wide Web, 1995 (Box 85, Folder 9)
  - Department of Defense, 2000s (Box 85, Folder 10)
  - Department of Defense, 2000s (Box 85, Folder 11)
  - Department of Defense, 2000s (Box 85, Folder 12)
  - Department of Defense, 2000s (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - Department of Defense, 2000s (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - Department of Defense, 2000s (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - Digital History: A Guide to Gathering, Preserving, and Presenting the Past on the Web, 2006 (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - Digital Learning Interactive, 1990s (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - Digital Media and Policy Perspectives, 1990s (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - Digital Talk, 1980s (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - Early Digital Media, 1988-1993 (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Educause Review, 2003 (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Electronic History Book, 1992-1993 (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Electronics and the Dim Future of the University, 1995 (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Envisioning the Future, 1997 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - Forum On Technology and Education, 1999 (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Forum On Technology and Education, 1999 (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Genealogical Computing, 1999 (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Guide To the Collections of the Smithsonian Video history Program, 1992-1996 (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - History Computer Review, 1996 (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - History Computer Review, 1997 (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - History Computer Review, 1997 (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - History Computer Review, 1998 (Box 87, Folder 12)
  - History Computer Review, 1999 (Box 87, Folder 13)
  - History Computer Review, 1999 (Box 87, Folder 14)
  - History Computer Review, 2000 (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - History Computer Review, 2000 (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - History Computer Review, 2001 (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - History Computer Review, 2002 (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - History Computer Review, 2002 (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - History Journals and the Electronic Future, 1997 (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - History Microcomputer Review, 1994 (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - Hypertext and Scholarship, 1990s-2000s (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - Marco Polo: Internet Content For Your Classroom, 2000s (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - Media Interactive Festival, 1994 (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - Media: Magazines, Articles, Pamphlets, 1990s (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - Media: Magazines, Articles, Pamphlets, 1990s (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - NEH in the Digital Age, 1990s (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - Networking and Computing, 1990s (Box 88, Folder 14)
  - New Media Archives, 2004-2005 (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - New Media Articles and Papers, 1997 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - New Media Book, 2003-2005 (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - New Media Classroom II, 1997 (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - New Media Education, 2005 (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - New Media Libraries, 2000s (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - New Media Narrative, 2000s (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - New Media Public History, 2000s (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - New Media Report, 1990s (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - NFS Education, 2000s (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Noble Review, 1990s-2000s (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Noble Review, 1990s-2000s (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Online Research Survey, March 2005 (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Open Source Grants, 2000s (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Papers About Online Research, 2000-2001 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - PCTV, 1990s (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Progress Report: Internet Content for the Classroom, 1999 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Project Jukebox: Where Oral History and Technology Come Together, 1992 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Project Muse History and Progress Report, 1998 (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Reading and Writing with Microcosm and HIDES, 1990s (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Report on the Evaluation of Five Points, 1993 (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - Research Agenda for Networked Cultural Heritage, 1996 (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - Scarcity and Abundance Review, 2000s (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - School for Scanning: Issues of Preservation and Access for Paper-Based Collections, 1990s (Box 90, Folder 14)
  - School for Scanning: Issues of Preservation and Access for Paper-Based Collections, 1990s (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - School for Scanning: Issues of Preservation and Access for Paper-Based Collections, 1990s (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - School for Scanning: Working in a Digital World, 1996 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - School for Scanning: Working in a Digital World, 1996 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - School for Scanning: Working in a Digital World, 1996 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Social Education, 2003 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Syllabus, 2002 (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Technological Learning Notes, 1990s-2000s (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Technology, Learning and Equity, 1990s (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Technology: Magazines, Articles, Pamphlets and Writings, 1990s (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Tentative Plans for Writing Workshop, 1980s (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - The Civil War Hypermedia Project, 1990s (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - The Five Points: The Design of a Multimedia Program on Social History, 1993 (Box 91, Folder 13)
  - The Library of Congress Request for Proposals for Digital Images, 1996 (Box 91, Folder 14)
  - Voyager and Voyager Notes, 1990s (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Web Articles, 1990s (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Web wise Talk, 2007 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Who Built America? An Electronic Book, 1990 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Wikipedia, 2000s (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Writing the History of the Internet, 2000s (Box 92, Folder 6)
- Series 7: Media, 1980s-2007; (5 boxes)
  Contains CDs, VHS, cassettes and computer disks.
  - Slides, 1980s (Box 93, Folder 1)
    Slides of historical images of the New York Central Park area and photographs of park activity in the 1980s.
  - Bio backup b, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Central Park Bio DBF, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - CP 58 11, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - CP 58 6, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - CP 58 8, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - CP 58 9, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - CP Bib. DBF 1, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - CP Bib. DBF 2, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - CP Bibliography, Pictures, and Bio, 1993 (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - CP00 1 B, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - CP00 2 B, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - CP00 3 B, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 12)
  - CP00 4 B, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 13)
  - CP00 5 B, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - CP00 6 B, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 15)
  - CP00a, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 16)
  - CP00b, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 17)
  - CP1 Backup b, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 18)
  - CP1 Backup b, part 2, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 19)
  - CP41 B 1, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 20)
  - CP419, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 21)
  - CP58 10, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 22)
  - CP58 7, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 23)
  - CP58b, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 24)
  - CPS8 3, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 25)
  - CPS8 4, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 26)
  - CPS8a, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 27)
  - CPS8c, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 28)
  - CPSO, 1992 (Box 94, Folder 29)
  - CPSO DBF, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 30)
  - CPUB 3, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 31)
  - FLO Indexes, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 32)
  - May Papers DBF, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 33)
  - MSS00 DBF 1, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 34)
  - MSS00 DBF 2, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 35)
  - MSS00 DBF 3, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 36)
  - Real Estate Memos and Outline, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 37)
  - S8 1, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 38)
  - S8 2, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 39)
  - S8 5, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 40)
  - Unidentified Disk, 1990s (Box 94, Folder 41)
  - American Historical Production, Inc. "Roy Rosenzweig Demonstration of Who Built America?", undated (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - American's Answer, undated (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Armenian National Institute "Everyone's Not Here: Families of the Armenian Genocide", undated (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - CFMandL American Social History Project Demo Reel for WBA CD Rom, 1990s (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Children of Labor, undated (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Historic Fairfax, Inc. "Recollections of Fairfax", 1985 (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Image as Artifact, undated (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Student Video Center George Mason University Dr. Cynthia Enloe Class #24 "Feminists Take a Look at the Global Sneaker.", 1995 (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - To Dream Tomorrow: A Portrait of Ada Lovelace, 2003 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - WBA? CD Rom Film Excerpts, undated (Box 95, Folder 10)
  - American Impressions Volume One, 1995 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Blank Tape, undated (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Carl Winter, 1973 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - FDR/Kennedy Inaugural, undated (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Frank Trager, 1973 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - GAHM The Great American History Machine, 1995 (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Jurassic Park Voyager, 1990-1991 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - National Museum of American Art, 1996 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - The Dreamer and the Doer LaGuardia: Labor/ Aviation, 1980s (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - The Dreamer and the Doer LaGuardia: Reformer Health and Housing, 1980s (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - The Dreamer and the Doer LaGuardia: The Last Days, 1980s (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - The Dreamer and the Doer LaGuardia: The Physical City/ Relief, 1980s (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - The Industrial Revolution in America, 1995 (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - The Valley of the Shadow: Two Communities in the American Civil War, 2000 (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - Time Traveler CD, 1992 (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Tracing the Decay of Fiction: Encounters with a Film by Pat O'Neill, 2002 (Box 96, Folder 16)
  - First Kennedy-Nixon Debate, Chicago, Illinois, September 26, 1960 (Box 98)
  - Who Built America?, 1993 (Box 98)
- Series 8: Oversize, 1934-1972; (1 box)
  Oversized Material such as photographs, prints and an atlas.
  - Atlas of Worcester, Massachusetts, 1971 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Franklin Roosevelt Photograph, 1934 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Leisure Photograph, undated (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Let's Make a Deal Print, undated (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Marx Brothers "Night at the Opera" Photograph, 1972 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Russian Print, 1930s (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Strom Thurmond Photograph, undated (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - The Historian Print, undated (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Washburn and Moen Manufacturing Company, Worcester, Massachusetts, undated (Box 97, Folder 9)
- Series 9: Electronic Files, 1995-2007; (3.06 GB; 9,776 electronic files)
  Includes three folders of electronic files that date from 1995-2007. These files are restricted.